## NG Wing Yi, Sandy

sandy@fiveelephant.com, +49 177 8926 362

#### **PERSONAL SUMMARY:**

Passionate in coffee making and would like to develop my career in specialty coffee industry. Being an open-minded and positive team player, with the ability to work alone. Willing to take challenges where I can contribute & develop my abilities, and continue to enhance experience. My dream is to set up my own cafe, with a team from different cultural backgrounds.

# **KEY SKILLS AND TECHNIQUES:**

- Willingness & motivation to acquire new knowledge and skills.
- Creativity and open-minded to new ideas.
- Quick Learner with competent knowledge of food and beverage.
- Effective communication skills under stress and time constraints.
- Time management and ability to multitask.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

WORK EXIENCE.	
09/2019 - Present	<ul> <li>Five Elephant Roastery &amp; Cafe (Berlin, Germany), Barista - Executive Assistant.</li> <li>Implement systems for facilitating cafes' operations.</li> <li>Organized and participated in several major coffee events, including World of Coffee, Berlin Coffee Festival and La Marzocco Residency.</li> <li>Cooperate with store managers to achieve financial and service goals.</li> </ul>
06/2017 - 06/2018	<ul> <li>Platform 7 Coffee (Vancouver), Barista All-rounder.</li> <li>Work on different brewing methods, including Hario and Chemex pour over, aeropress and</li> </ul>
	Musette Caffe (Vancouver), Barista All-rounder.
04/2017 - 06/2017	<ul> <li>Café Deadend (Hong Kong), Bar Manager.</li> <li>Design a new summer beverage menu, with new ideas from Melbourne experience.</li> <li>Develop the specialty coffee menu, including cold-brew, aeropress, and pour over.</li> <li>Recruit and train new bar staff, and cultivate a good team spirit.</li> <li>Promote and advertise the cafe on social media.</li> </ul>
10/2016 - 04/2017	<ul> <li>Millstone Patisserie (Malvern, Melbourne), Head Barista.</li> <li>Capable of handling daily consumption of 3-5 kg for weekdays.</li> <li>Cooperate with another barista on weekends under a fast-paced coffee and beverage order.</li> <li>Develop new recipes for beverage (smoothies and juices).</li> <li>Stock control for bar supplies and other beverages.</li> </ul>
04/2015 - 10/2016	<ul> <li>La Tropezienne Patisserie (Glenfierre, Melbourne), Barista all-rounder.</li> <li>Handling food, coffee and other beverages.</li> <li>Organise and arrange stock items.</li> <li>Handle orders and cashier.</li> <li>Training new staff at coffee and daily operation.</li> </ul>
02/2016 - 08/2016	<ul> <li>Rumbles Patisserie (Prahran, Melbourne), Barista,</li> <li>Ensure consistency and quality beverages and services for customers everyday.</li> <li>Daily shop opening and closing.</li> <li>Communicate with kitchen about orders and customers' comments.</li> </ul>
09/2013 - 03/2015	<ul> <li>Café Deadend (Hong Kong), All-rounder:</li> <li>Greet everyone with warm and friendly smile.</li> <li>Ensure timely, accurate delivery of all food &amp; beverages.</li> <li>Assist the head barista for coffee &amp; beverages making.</li> <li>Respond to enquiries in a polite and constructive manner.</li> <li>Maintain cleanliness in the shop during/ after operation.</li> <li>Handle orders and cashier.</li> <li>Build good customers relationship.</li> </ul>

### **EDUCATION:**

09/2008 - 06/2011	The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong BA (HONS) in Fashion & Textiles
01/2010 - 06/2010	Cornell University, College of Human Ecology, Ithaca, NY Undergraduate Exchange Programme. Fiber Science and Apparel Design (Junior)

**PERSONAL: Language Skills:** Proficiency in spoken and written English and Chinese (Cantonese and Mandarin). Knowledge of Japanese and Spanish. Learning German.